circuit.co.uk 2019-03-14

# Privacy and Cookies - Circuit

Circuit Launderette Services Limited (trading as Circuit), (“We”) is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. We collect, use and are responsible for certain personal information about you. When we do so we are subject to the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) which applies across the European Union (including in the United Kingdom), any other applicable data protection laws. We are responsible as ‘controller’ of that personal information for the purposes of those laws.

This policy sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us.  Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

**1\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT FROM YOU**

We will collect and process the following information about you:

**Information you give us.** This is information about you that you give us by filling in forms on our website or by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise. It includes information you provide when you use our site, top up your laundry cards, subscribe to a mailing list, interact through webchat or request more information and when you report a problem with our site or a service or operational issue. The information you give us may include your name, address, date of birth, e-mail address and phone number, payment details such as credit card or bank account details, your responses to surveys.

**Information we collect about you.** With regard to each of your visits to our site we will automatically collect the following information:

Technical information, including the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, any login information, details entered into any form submission, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser versions, operating system and platform, device and device types.

Information about your visit, including the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL), clickstream to, through and from our site (including date and time), page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), methods used to browse away from the page and any phone number used to call our customer service number.

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates.  If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.  Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

**Information we receive from other sources.** We collect most information from you directly as explained above however we may also collect information from publicly accessible sources or directly from a third party. We are working closely with third parties (including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers, search information providers). They may provide the information collected when you visit our sites or otherwise as set out above.

**2\. HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION**

We use information held about you in the following ways:

**Information you give to us.** We will use this information:

To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us and to provide you with the information, products and services that you request from us;

To notify you about changes to our service;

To deal with payment queries and problems with card top ups or other payment systems

To ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner;

For our marketing purposes we would like to contact you by post, email, SMS and telephone about goods and services that we provide that we think you may be interested in and where we have a legitimate interest to do so. We will only contact you by electronic means (e-mail or SMS) where we have your consent to do so. You can tell us to stop marketing you at any time;

To provide you, or permit selected third parties to provide you, with information by post, email, SMS and telephone about other goods or services that we feel may interest you. Where we permit selected third parties to use your data, we will only do this where we are satisfied that there is a legitimate interest to do so and we (or they) will only contact you by electronic means if you have consented to this.

**Information we collect about you.** We will use this information:

To administer our site and for internal operations, including, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes;

To improve our site to ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner;

As part of our efforts to keep our site safe and secure;

To measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you;

To make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our site about goods or services that may interest you or them.

**Information we receive from other sources.** We will combine this information with information you give to us and information we collect about you. We will use this information and the combined information for the purposes set out above (depending on the types of information we receive).

**3\. REASONS WE CAN COLLECT AND USE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

The law on data protection sets out a number of different legal grounds upon which organisations can rely to allow the collection and processing of personal data. We rely on the following as set out below 

**Consent**

In some cases we will specifically ask for your consent to process your data e.g. by ticking a box or confirming verbally that you consent. In these cases we will always clearly explain what we will do with your data and will keep a record of your consent.

**Contractual Obligations**

In other cases, we will need to use your personal data to actually do what you are asking us to do and to perform our contract with you. E.g. to help with payment or card top up issues we will need your name and card number.

**Legal Compliance**

If the law requires us to, we may need to collect and process your data to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations.

**Legitimate Interest**

In specific situations, we require your data to pursue our legitimate interests in a way which might reasonably be expected as part of running our business and which does not materially impact your rights, freedom or interests. For example, we will use your purchase history to send you or make available personalised offers that we think will be of interest to you and your business. We will also use your address and phone number to contact you with direct marketing information by post and phone, telling you about products and services that we think may be of interest to you and your business.

**4\. WHO WE SHARE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION WITH**

We share your personal information;

With any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006.

With selected third parties including:

Business partners, suppliers, and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with them or you;

Website & app hosts and analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the operation, improvement and optimisation of our site;

We only allow our service providers to handle your personal information if we are satisfied they take appropriate measures to protect your personal information. We also impose contractual obligations on service providers relating to ensure they can only use your personal information to provide services to us and to you.

In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we will disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets. The recipient of the information will be bound by confidentiality obligations.

**5\. OUR MARKETING**

We may use your personal information to send you updates (by email, text message, telephone or post) about our products or services, including exclusive offers, promotions or new products or services.

We have a legitimate interest in processing your personal information for promotional purposes. This means we do not usually need your consent to send you promotional communications. However, where consent is needed, we will ask for this consent separately and clearly.

We will always treat your personal information with the utmost respect and never sell or share it with other organisations outside the group for marketing purposes. We do however work closely with our payment partner PayPal and from time to time we may carry out joint promotions to offer you discounts or savings or chances to win prizes. These communications may come from us or Pay Pal and whilst we will share information with them relating to the fact that you are a customer of ours, the personal data that they have about you will be information that they already hold as a result of you also being a PayPal customer.

You have the right to opt out of receiving promotional communications at any time by;

Contacting us at [info@circuitcardtopup.com](mailto:info@circuitcardtopup.com)

Adjusting your preferences in your Circuit Laundry ‘my account’ details [click here](https://www.circuit.co.uk/i-want-to-do-my-laundry/my-circuit/update-details/)

Using the “unsubscribe” link in emails or “STOP” number in text messages

**6\. WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

Information may be held at our offices and those of our group companies, third party agencies, service providers, representatives and agents as described above. (See above “Who we share your personal information with”)

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, and processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. These transfers are subject to special rules under the applicable data protection laws as some non-EEA countries (such as the United States of America) do not have the same level of data protection laws as the United Kingdom and EEA. We will ensure that any transfer to one of these countries complies with data protection law. Our standard practice is to use standard data protection “model” clauses that have been approved by the European Commission. If you would like further information please contact us. 

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL technology. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

**7\. H** **O** **W LONG WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION FOR**

We will keep your personal information while you have a Circuit payment card or Circuit Mobile App Account which you continue to top up with us. Thereafter, we will keep your personal information for as long as is necessary:

To respond to any questions, complaints or claims made by you or on your behalf;

To show that we treated you fairly;

To keep records as required by law.

We will not retain your personal information for longer than necessary for the purposes set out in this policy. Different retention periods apply for different types of personal information. When it is no longer necessary to retain your personal information, we will delete or anonymise it.

**8\. YOUR RIGHTS**

You have the following rights, which you can exercise free of charge:

**Access  
**The right to be provided with a copy of your personal information (the right of access)

**Rectification  
**The right to require us to correct any mistakes in your personal information

**To be forgotten  
**The right to require us to delete your personal information—in certain situations

**Restriction of processing  
**The right to require us to restrict processing of your personal information—in certain circumstances, e.g. if you contest the accuracy of the data

**Data portability**

The right to receive the personal information you provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and/or transmit that data to a third party—in certain situations

**To object  
**The right to object:

  * at any time to your personal information being processed for direct marketing (including profiling);
  * in certain other situations to our continued processing of your personal information, e.g. processing carried out for the purpose of our legitimate interests.

**Not to be subject to automated individual decision-making  
**The right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing (including profiling) that produces legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affects you

For further information on each of those rights, including the circumstances in which they apply, please contact us or see the Guidance from the UK Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) on individuals’ rights under the General Data Protection Regulation.

If you would like to exercise any of those rights, please contact our Data Privacy Manager: [info@circuitcardtopup.com](mailto:info@circuitcardtopup.com)

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data.  You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at [info@circuitcardtopup.com](mailto:info@circuitcardtopup.com)

**9\. COOKIES**

Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve our site. 

We may store so called “cookies” on your computer when you visit our website. This allows us to recognise your computer the next time you visit us. The type of information we collect as a result of a cookie is specific to your computer and may include the Internet Protocol (IP) address, the date and time you access our website and what parts of the website are visited. We collect the foregoing information to monitor the usage and usefulness of our website; we only use this information for statistical analysis purposes. You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

### Cookies we use:

Cookie | Name | Purpose | More information  
---|---|---|---  
| 

  * _utma
  * _utmb
  * _utmc
  * _utmz

| These cookies are used to measure visitor behaviour and usage patterns, such as the time spent on site, number of visits or what pages were viewed during a visit.All information is anonymous and reports always show aggregate, not individual data. | Click here for an overview of privacy at Google  
| 

  * adiErradiV

| AdInsight uses cookies to anonymously track a visitors behaviour on a website so the business can improve the users experience when navigating through the website. | You can opt out of tracking by AdInsight by setting the DoNotTrack feature in your browser (most of the latest browsers are supported).For more information on enabling the DoNotTrack feature in each browser please follow the links below:General information about DoNotTrack: <http://donottrack.us/>

How to enable DoNotTrack in Mozilla Firefox: <http://dnt.mozilla.org/>

How to enable DoNotTrack in Internet Explorer: <http://ie.microsoft.com/testdrive/Browser/DoNotTrack/Default.html>

How to enable DoNotTrack in Safari: <http://osxdaily.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/safari-lion-do-not-track.jpg>

How to enable DoNotTrack in Chrome (an additional plugin is required): <https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/ckdcpbflcbeillmamogkpmdhnbeggfja>  
  
******10\. CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

Any changes we make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy. This policy was last reviewed and amended in May 2018.

**CONTACT**

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to the Data Privacy Manager at [info@circuitcardtopup.com](mailto:info@circuitcardtopup.com)

We hope that our Data Privacy Manager can resolve any query or concern you may have about our use of your information.

You can lodge a complaint with the UK supervisory authority, the Information Commissioner who may be contacted at <https://ico.org.uk/concerns> or telephone: 0303 123 1113.
